<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Abdelhak's Blog</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/</link><description>Recent content on Abdelhak's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doom Emacs Configuration</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/config/</guid><description>This repository How to install Emacs stuff Intro This file Doom configuration files Pseudo early-init Doom modules (init.el) File skeleton Input (:input) General (:config) Completion (:completion) User interface (:ui) Editor (:editor) Emacs builtin stuff (:emacs) Terminals (:term) Checkers (:checkers) Tools (:tools) Operating system (:os) Language support (:lang) Email (:email) Apps (:app) Private modules (:private) Additional packages (packages.el) General Emacs settings User information Secrets Better defaults File deletion Window Split defaults Undo and auto-save Editing Emacs sources Frame Maximizing Focus created frame Margins Chemacs2 Emacs daemon Initialization Tweaks Save recent files Package configuration Check for external tools User interface Font Theme Mode line Clock Battery Mode line customization Set transparency Dashboard Custom splash image Dashboard Which key Window title Fringe Vertico Company SVG tag Focus Smooth scrolling All the icons Editing Scratch buffer Mouse buttons Page break lines Binary files Very large files Evil Aggressive indent YASnippet Literate configuration Allow babel execution in doom CLI actions Asynchronous tangling IDE Centaur tabs Treemacs Projectile Tramp Eros-eval dir-locals.</description></item><item><title>Push partition image to an Android phone</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/push-partition-android/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 04:12:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/push-partition-android/</guid><description>Prepare your device In your Android phone, enter recovery mode and enable ADB (usually, you need a custom recovery like TWRP, OrangeFox or LineageOS&amp;#39; recovery… etc). On a Linux machine, forward a local TCP port to a remote port on the Android device (let say local 6789, remote 9876). adb forward tcp:6789 tcp:9876 adb shell Netcat your file Once connected to the device&amp;#39;s shell, start netcat in listen mode on port 9876, and redirect stdout to the partition block device:</description></item><item><title>Restore a partimage to a smaller disk</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/restore-partimage-small-disk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/restore-partimage-small-disk/</guid><description>Sometimes; when working with partimage, someone can create a backup of a 1TB partition which contains -for example- only 10GB of data; in this case, when we want to restore it, partimage will fail if the restore disk does not have enough space (1TB in this case).
I faced this problem and here the trick I used to restore the backup image to a smaller disk image.
Create an image file Create an image file with the right size (with seek, we don&amp;#39;t need to actually have the whole space):</description></item></channel></rss>