<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My posts on Abdelhak's Blog</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/</link><description>Recent content in My posts on Abdelhak's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doom Emacs Configuration</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/config/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/config/</guid><description>Intro I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux exclusively since 2010, GNU Emacs was always installed on my machine, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t discover the real Emacs until 2020, in the beginning, I started my Vanilla Emacs configuration from scratch, but after a while, it becomes a mess. As a new Emacs user, I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the in the beginning how to optimize my configuration and how to do things correctly. I discovered then Spacemacs, which made things much easier, but it was a little slow, and just after, I found the awesome Doom Emacs, and since, I didn&amp;rsquo;t quit my Emacs screen!</description></item><item><title>Push partition image to an Android phone</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/push-partition-android/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 04:12:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/push-partition-android/</guid><description>Prepare your device In your Android phone, enter recovery mode and enable ADB (usually, you need a custom recovery like TWRP, OrangeFox or LineageOS&amp;#39; recovery… etc). On a Linux machine, forward a local TCP port to a remote port on the Android device (let say local 6789, remote 9876). adb forward tcp:6789 tcp:9876 adb shell Netcat your file Once connected to the device&amp;#39;s shell, start netcat in listen mode on port 9876, and redirect stdout to the partition block device:</description></item><item><title>Restore a partimage to a smaller disk</title><link>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/restore-partimage-small-disk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abdelhakbougouffa.pro/posts/restore-partimage-small-disk/</guid><description>Sometimes; when working with partimage, someone can create a backup of a 1TB partition which contains -for example- only 10GB of data; in this case, when we want to restore it, partimage will fail if the restore disk does not have enough space (1TB in this case).
I faced this problem and here the trick I used to restore the backup image to a smaller disk image.</description></item></channel></rss>